<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE versions SYSTEM "../dtd/versions.dtd">

<versions>
  <title>Version History</title>

  <version>
    <title>Version 1.0.b2</title>
    <date>2008-07-28</date>

    <item>New rules added in the Titles, Subheadings and Form Controls subsections of Navigation &amp; Orientation.</item>

    <item>Rule evaluation result messages at the Page Report level have been reworked according to the following scheme: When the result is 'pass', no additional information is provided; when the result is 'warn' or 'fail', the number of elements that do not meet the criteria for passing the rule is reported.</item>
  </version>

  <version>
    <title>Version 1.0.b1</title>
    <date>2008-07-21</date>

    <item>FAE is now based on the <a class="external" href="http://www.djangoproject.com">Django web application framework</a> written in the <a class="external" href="http://python.org">Python programming language</a>. As in previous versions, it also consists of an analysis engine written in <a class="external" href="http://caml.inria.fr/ocaml/index.en.html">Objective CAML</a> and a <a class="external" href="http://www.postgresql.org/">PostgreSQL DBMS</a>.</item>

    <item>New rules have been added, and existing rules modified, based on the <a class="external" href="http://www.dhs.state.il.us/iitaa/">IITAA</a> Implementation Guidelines. These include all rules in the Titles, Subheadings and Form Controls subsections of the Navigation &amp; Orientation section of Page and Sitewide Reports.</item>

    <item>Manage Reports feature: A registered user may now select up to five reports (by default) to be permanently archived. Additionally, the last five reports that have been generated but not marked for permanent archival are also saved.</item>

    <item>Reports that do not meet the above criteria are now automatically purged based on their age (currently after they are two days old).</item>

    <item>Usage statistics are now collected via automated script, and can be viewed from the About FAE menu under Usage Statistics.</item>

    <item>Run FAE changes: The default Run FAE form for authenticated users now accepts only a single URL. To analyze multiple URLs, select the Multiple URLs link in the top menu bar.</item>

    <item>Page Report header information now includes the Page Title content.</item>

    <item>The URL for linking directly to FAE has changed. Please see the <a href="/about/overview/">About FAE: Overview</a> page for details.</item>
  </version>

  <version>
    <title>Pre-1.0 versions</title>
    <item>Change history for older versions of FAE can be found at <a href="/about/versions_old/">Pre-1.0 Versions</a>.</item>
  </version>
</versions>
